Dark and difficult times lie ahead.
Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire is a adventure,
fantasy film directed by Mike Newell.
When Harry Potter's name emerges from the Goblet of Fire, he becomes a competitor in a
grueling battle for glory among three wizarding schools—the Triwizard Tournament.
But since Harry never submitted his name for the Tournament, who did?
Now Harry must confront a deadly dragon, fierce water demons and an enchanted maze
only to find himself in the cruel grasp of He Who Must Not Be Named.
Harry Potter, played by Daniel Radcliffe.
Ron Weasley, played by Rupert Grint.
Hermione Granger, played by Emma Watson.
Alastor 'Mad-Eye' Moody, played by Brendan Gleeson.
Albus Dumbledore, played by Michael Gambon.
Cedric Diggory, played by Robert Pattinson.
Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire is a 2005 fantasy film directed
by Mike Newell from a screenplay by Steve Kloves.
It is based on the 2000 novel Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire by J.
It is the sequel to Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban (2004) and
the fourth instalment in the Harry Potter film series.
The film stars Daniel Radcliffe as Harry Potter, alongside Rupert Grint and Emma Watson
as Harry's best friends Ron Weasley and Hermione Granger, respectively.
The story follows Harry's fourth year at Hogwarts, as he is chosen by the
Goblet of Fire to compete in the Triwizard Tournament.
Principal photography began in early 2004, and the film
premiered worldwide on 18 November 2005.
Five days following release, it had earned over US$102 million at the North American box office, the third-highest
first-weekend tally for a Harry Potter film behind Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows – Part 1 and Part 2.
Goblet of Fire enjoyed a successful run at the box office, grossing $896 million worldwide and becoming
the highest-grossing film of 2005 and the sixth-highest-grossing film in the series.
The film was nominated for the Academy Award for Best Art Direction
and won the BAFTA Award for Best Production Design.
Goblet of Fire was the second film in the series to be released in IMAX.
The film received positive reviews.
It was followed by Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix in 2007.
The film explores themes of witch, dying and death, based
on novel or book, magic, boarding school.